One woman can change the course of history
Queen of the Desert is a drama, adventure, history
film directed by Werner Herzog.
A chronicle of Gertrude Bell's life, a traveler, writer, archaeologist, explorer, cartographer, and political
attaché for the British Empire in the Near and Middle East at the dawn of the twentieth century.
Her knowledge of the tribal leaders is used by the British to
establish the Kingdoms of Iraq, Jordan and Saudi Arabia.
Gertrude Bell, played by Nicole Kidman.
Henry Cadogan, played by James Franco.
Richard Wylie, played by Damian Lewis.
Fattuh, Bell's guide, played by Jay Abdo.
T.E. Lawrence, played by Robert Pattinson.
Florence Bell, played by Jenny Agutter.
Queen of the Desert is a 2015 American epic biographical drama film written and directed by Werner Herzog and is based on the
life of British traveller, writer, archaeologist, explorer, cartographer and political officer Gertrude Bell.
The film follows Bell's life chronologically, from
her early twenties until her death.
It was Herzog's first feature film in six years after his
2009 film My Son, My Son, What Have Ye Done?
The film stars Nicole Kidman, James Franco, Damian Lewis and Robert Pattinson.
After going through many delays and casting problems, production finally took place
from December 2013 to March 2014 in Morocco, Jordan and England.
It was screened in the main competition section of the 65th Berlin
International Film Festival and had its premiere on February 6, 2015.
It had a theatrical release in Germany on September 3, 2015.
The film received mostly negative reviews from critics and was also a major financial
disappointment, grossing $2 million against a $36 million production budget.
The film explores themes of middle east, persia,
unrequited love, travel writer, adventurer.
The tone is emotional.